And now, presenting Mokku, the rarest wooden puppet in the world, who moves freely without strings and even sings!
First, Mokku will sing and walk!
Come on, Mokku, sing. Sing!
B-But I don't know any songs!
Idiot, just make something up!
But I... You bastard, you know what'll happen if you don't sing.
Come on! That's it, go!
Tears fall when you're sad
I'm just a sad
Wooden puppet
And now, ladies and gentlemen, next up is a delightful puppet dance, the polka!
Hey, dance!
But... I-I can't dance... Idiot! Just dance however you want!
Uh...
There!
I'll take some tea.
(Laughter)
A new video anime has come out. I explained about the animation unit, but this really rakes in the cash!
Mokku...
I feel bad for him, but he's about to go through something way worse.
That's right. We puppets are just playthings for humans.
They work you to the bone, and in the end, they throw you into the fire.
No matter how terribly we're treated, it can't be helped. We've been puppets from the day we were made.
Grandpa...
[[NO AUDIO]]
Mokku, where did you go? I'm all alone again...
Please come home, my Mokku.
I'm sorry, Grandpa.
Have you come to your senses yet, Mokku? Didn't I tell you back at the junk shop? Grandpa is the one you should feel sorry for, not yourself.
Grandpa's so worried about you he can't sleep. He even sold his coat and caught a cold.
And forgetting his kindness makes you an awful guy, Mokku.
Oh? Did that make you mad, Mokku?
I'm going to work for Grandpa.
Well, I'll be. Where on earth?
I'll work here and buy Grandpa an overcoat before I go home.
Hahaha! That's why you're so naive.
The world doesn't work that easily. You'd better give up.
Hmph. I've had enough of your meddling.
Take my advice, Mokku. If you trust humans too much, you'll make a fool of yourself. Hey, Mokku!
Shut up!
He's gone...
Whatever. Good riddance to that annoying pest...
Well, if it isn't Mokku!
Um... Oyakata?
What!
Starting tomorrow, I'm going to work as hard as I can for you, Oyakata!
Well, that's an admirable attitude. If you're going to be cooperative, it'll save me the trouble of yelling at you.
In return, though...
What?
I want you to give me a share of what I earn.
What?!
Give it back!
You little...
[[NO AUDIO]]
I see! Hahahahahaha!
If you're gonna become more popular and work hard, I've got no complaints. Fine, I'll give you a cut.
Thank you, Oyakata! I'll do my best. / Good, good boy. I'll give you plenty, so go on to sleep now.
Okay.
Stupid puppet.
I'm coming right back!
Coming back!
Ta-da!
[[APPLAUSE]]
[[LAUGHTER]]
I'm making a fortune here!
Um, Boss!
Got something to say?
About my promised share... I'm worried about Grandpa, so please let me go home.
What?! You idiot!
You think you can leave after earning this measly bit?
But you promised... / Shut up!
Ah!
Hey!
I never intended to give you a single penny from the start!
You'll work until you break into pieces!
Understand, you fool?!
(coughing)
Poor Mokku. In the end, we puppets are just playthings for humans.
Grandpa...
Mokku, just give up. We're puppets.
Humans work us to the bone, and once we break, they burn us. That's the end of it.
The Cricket was right. I was wrong.
Ah...
I worked for that money. It's mine.
If I take it home, I can buy Grandpa an overcoat and anything else he needs.
Like hell I'll let that monster of a boss keep it all to himself!
All right.
Mokku, what are you going to do?
I'm going to avenge everyone.
Stop it, Mokku. Don't you know how terrifying Oyakata is?
He'll smash you to pieces and throw you into the stove!
Don't do it, Mokku.
(chirping)
I stole the key to get outside...
Good night.
(coughing)
(weeping)
(snoring)
Look, it worked. Mokku, run while you have the chance. Come on, hurry!
Let's all escape together!
We can't. We can't walk on our own like you, Mokku.
Don't worry about us. Get out of here, quick!
No!
All right.
There's no way I'm leaving you in a terrifying place like this!
(noise)
Whoa!
Huh?! What? Mokku!
That bastard's trying to run off after stealing my money?!
Wait!!
Wait, hold on!
You little... No! I worked hard for this money!
Now!
Like hell I'll let you get away!
Hahaha!
Hold it right there!
You thought you could get away from me?!
Don't worry about us, just run!
Hurry, run away on your own!
Mokku, don't worry about us!
Mokku!
Grrr...
Aaaargh!
Hold it, damn it!
I'm sorry we ran away!
Hey, get back here!
Ah, he's coming!
Wait! Wait, wait, wait, hold on!
Aaah!
Aaah! Help me!
Aaah! Aaah!
(Screams)
Why do I have to suffer like this?
Because I'm a puppet...
I hate this... Being a puppet... I want to become human.
I want to become human!
Mokku, I am the Fairy of the Oak Tree, your birthplace.
Oh, then you're the one who brought me to life!
I don't want to be a puppet anymore. I want to become human!
I do not possess that power.
What? Then I can never become human?
You can.
Mokku, becoming human is entirely up to you.
What should I do? Please, tell me!
Always be a good boy. If you have a righteous and kind heart, you will surely become human.
Really?
It is true. You must always strive to have a good and kind heart.
I'll try my best to have a good, kind heart. And I'll definitely become human.
I'll be looking forward to that day, Mokku.
Goodbye, Mokku.
A good heart, a kind heart...
Mokku, won't you ever come back home to me?
I could never make another you again.
Was I just hearing things?
(Grandpa!)
Mokku!
Grandpa!
Grandpa, I'm sorry. I'll be a good boy. I'll become human. I'll go to school, too.
Mokku... Mokku...
[[NO AUDIO]]
- I'm off! - Alright.
Grandpa, I'm heading out!
- Take care. - Okay!
Go straight to school, now.
Ah, ha, ha, ugh...
You're called Mokku, aren't you?
I know a really fun place.
Really?
Come on, let's go together!
Mokku, it's such a wonderful place.
Hmph! No way!
(Music)
Okay! Wait for me!
Mokku and Grandfather lived very happily together.
However, because Grandfather doted only on Mokku, Redbeard the mouse, who had lived there first, grew jealous.
Scheming with Kenken the fox and his gang, Redbeard pushes Mokku into the river.
After swallowing so much freezing river water, will Mokku be able to revive?
Look forward to next week's Kashi no Ki Mokku!